Let’s see what we come up with when analyzing
this code and answering the questions of the
four print statements. First, the symbol on line
4 is a modulus symbol, which means the remainder
of 500 (x) divided by 6 is the answer. 500
divided by 6 is 83 with a remainder of 2,
so 2 is the modulus. Next, the code on line
6 is multiplying x by 3 and assigning the new
value to x. Note that in the print statement
on line 4, no assignments are taking place,
but in this code on lines 6 and 7, an assignment
is indeed taking place, so x times 3 is 1500,
and because this code contains an assignment,
x is now 1500. Looking at the code on line 9,
x, being 1500, is greater than y, 200, but
x is not in the list of values of z. Thus,
this print statement should return false. The
last print statement is somewhat of a visual trap,
and I purposely created this trap so that
you can avoid it both on the exam and when
you are building apps in Python. We will
see the trap in just a moment, but first,
always apply order of operations, when applicable,
to a condition. We have an or and we have a not.
Not takes precedence over or. Thus, we want to
evaluate y not in z first, which is true. Next,
let’s look for the trap. The trap is to look at a
variable assignment at the top of a code block and
forget that the variable has changed since then.
When trying to deduce an answer such as this one,
follow a variable from its start all the way
through the code to the spot where you need
to analyze the variable’s value at this point.
If we forget to do that, x starting at 500 and
then dividing by 5 to get an answer of 100 will
throw us off because, in between here and there,
x was tripled. Another way to look at this is to
track every assignment you see for a variable from
its start to the line of code being analyzed.
It turns out both these statements are true,
so the or keyword is not that relevant, as all
that is needed for this statement to be true is
for one of these conditions to be true. Let’s run
this code. We see the results. The first result
is indeed 2, the second result is 1500, the third
result is false, and the fourth result is true.